

nicolasmarin1312@gmail.com



Villa de Mayo, Buenos Aires, Argentina

## **SOCIAL LINKS**



in linkedin.com/in/rnicolasmarin



rnicolasmarin.github.io

# **ABOUT ME**

Native Android Developer with +3 years of experience. Experienced in remote work on teams in different locations, with multiple types of roles and using agile methodologies. I have worked as a freelance, full time employee and also on personal projects.

I'm passionate about building new apps or improving existing ones and I'm always looking for new concepts and topics to learn but also projects in which to put my knowledge to use. Right now I'm focusing on Compose as a newer way to design User Interfaces.

### **SKILLS**

- Languages: Java, Kotlin, Sql
- **UI**: Activities, Fragments, ViewBinding, DataBinding
- Android: ViewModel, LiveData, Coroutines, Service, BroadcastReceiver, Notification, Sharedpreferences,
- Android Libraries: Room, Retrofit, Volley, Gson, Glide, Hilt, Navigation, Paging
- Arquitecture/Patterns: MVVM, MVI, MVP, Repository, Clean Arquitecture, Use cases
- VCS: Git (GitLab, GitHub, Bitbucket, GitKraken, Gitflow)
- Other: Scrum, Slack, Teams, Zoom, Meet, Trello, Jira, Figma, Bitrise, JSON, XML, UnitTesting (JUnit), POO, Gradle, Firebase, Crashlytics, RxJava, Jsoup.

# **NICOLAS MARIN**

# ANDROID DEVELOPER

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

• Freelance Android Developer (Java):

Sep-Oct, 2020. QIERO App.

Building new screens while communicating constantly and acting on the feedback from the client at a delivery food MVP app for a startup from Chile.

Technologies: Java, Git, XML, JSON

Android Developer Jr/Ssr (Java/Kotlin):

Jan 2021-Nov 2022. PDS S.A.

Minor corrections, visual and logic changes, complex developments that would have a major impact at the whole ecosystem formed by several small apps that depends on a bigger main one for managing sales on food places for a local company with clients on 5 countries. Checking PR, assisting coworkers with less experience on the project and as developers.

<u>Technologies</u>: Kotlin, Java, Git, GitFlow, XML, JSON, Retrofit, SQLite, Room, Bitbucket, Hilt, Dependency Injection, Gradle, Crashlytics, Firebase, Unit Testing, JUnit

Android Developer Ssr (Kotlin):

Nov 2022 to now. Flux IT/Banco Galicia. Being part of a fully remote, multidisciplinary team including Mobile (Android/IOS), different layers of Backend, Design, Web, QA, PO, TO, Analyst and Scrum Master roles to develop new features or extend/fix some existing ones for the homebanking app from the Galicia bank.

<u>Technologies</u>: Kotlin, Coroutines, Git, GitFlow, XML, JSON, Retrofit, GitHub, Hilt, Dependency Injection, Gradle, Crashlytics, RxJava

#### COMPETENCE

I have the ability to work in teams, I'm analytical and a problem solver. I'm constantly seeking to improve and to learn more.

I also like sharing knowledge with others and I'm always ready for new challenges.

#### LANGUAGES

• Spanish: Native Level

• English: Intermediate Level

#### **EDUCATION**

Higher Technician in Computer Science (Tecnicatura Superior en Informática)

Universidad Nacional de General Sarmiento.

March 2016 - December 2018. Avarege Score: 8.21 **Subjetcs:** 

- Software Engineering
- Object-Oriented Programming
- Programming in Java
- Operating Systems
- Computer Networks
- Databases

#### CERTIFICATES

- Android Professional Course, Android with Kotlin, JAVA, Kotlin, by CodigoFacilito.
  - Introductory courses about developing on the android platform and the programming languages Kotlin and Java.
- <u>Building Industry-Level Apps With Multi-Module</u>
   <u>Architecture</u>, by Philipp Lackner
   Course about Multi-Module projects, including pros, cons, how and in which projects implement this type of architecture.
- <u>Professional App Development With CI/CD</u> by Philipp Lackner

Course about how to use Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery to build good quality projects and automate some parts of the proccess, with special focus on Native Android Apps.

 Mastering Automated Testing of Industry-Level Android Apps by Philipp Lackner

Course about automated testing for android apps and the different kind of tests that exists (Unit, Integration, End-To-End, UI Testing) using examples from a real-world app.

#### **PROJECTS**

#### PokeManager

An Android application to function as a Pokedex using the PokeApi and the paging library to load the data by pages. In this personal project I was looking to create a newer and better version of an app I built a few years ago but applying some of the concepts and good practices I've learned since I joined the industry, also focusing on the UI aspect and adding some extra features.